

# Shitab Mushfiq-ul Islam

Mobile Application Developer | UI/UX Enthusiast

My name is Shitab Mushfiq-ul Islam, and I am an Engineer & Researcher. For the outside world, I am an Android Developer at Sheba.xyz, but secretly I learn various tech skills to enrich my knowledge do more with a goal to become a complete Mobile Application Developer. I am also a UI/UX and design enthusiast and try to make good use of that knowledge on my development.

shitab.mailbox01@gmail.com

+88 01318551434

in linkedin.com/in/shitabmir

github.com/shitab14

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Jr. Software Engineer Sheba.xyz

08/2019 - Present Service Industry Contributions to

Banani, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- sManager: The Complete Business Solution for MSME (Android Application)
- Bondhu: Earn Money Online App (Android Application)
- Sheba.xyz Your Personal Assistant (Android Application)

## **Associate Training and Content Specialist** Therap Services

09/2018 - 12/2018 DD Industry

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Contributions

- Software Documentation, Release Notes, User Tutorials.
- User Support Issues

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

Android App: Signature Stash (2019)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.mr\_mir.signaturestash

#### DrawingBot (Android App for IOT Project) (2017)

- https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GIV52TZL02E
- https://github.com/shitab14/DrawingBot

## Brailliant: Braille Language Interpreter & Keyboard (2017)

Participated in Project Manifestation Fall'17 by Robotics Club of **BRAC** University

## **EDUCATION**

## **Computer Science and Engineering**

**BRAC University** 

Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### Science, High School

Dhaka Residential Model College

2013 Dhaka, Bangladesh

## Science, Secondary School Dhaka Residential Model College

Dhaka, Bangladesh

### **TOOLS AND TECH**



## **PUBLICATIONS**

3D Visualization of 2D/360° image and navigation in virtual reality through motion processing via smart phone sensors (2019)

accepted by The Engineering Reality of Virtual Reality for presentation at the IS&T Electronic Imaging 2019 Symposium.

https://www.ingentaconnect.com/content/ist/ei/2019/00002019/000 00002/art00005

#### Augmented Reality Education System in Developing Countries (2019)

accepted by The Engineering Reality of Virtual Reality, for presentation at the IS&T Electronic Imaging 2019 Symposium.

https://www.ingentaconnect.com/contentone/ist/ei/2019/00002019/0 0000002/art00010

### **ORGANIZATIONS**

Computer Vision and Intelligent System Lab, BRAC University (2018)

Member

BRACU Express (2017 - 2018)

Head of Design

BRACU Express (2016 - 2017)

Contributing Writer

BRAC University Chess Club (2017 - 2018)

Director of Press and Publication

## **LANGUAGES**

Enalish Bengali

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Spanish

Limited Working Proficiency Professional Working Proficiency

#### **INTERESTS**

Game Development

Cricket

**Table Tennis**